# Edgar Colón Barrientos

Senior Software Engineer

Location: Ciudad de México

- Email: edgar.colonb@gmail.com

Web: https://edgar-colon.mx/

- Phone: (+52) 7444328340

- Age: 34 years old

Min economic perception: \$59K
 MXN NET (80k before taxes)

#### **SUMMARY**

I have been developing products with web technologies since 2011. I really love coding and delivering software with the right quality and I think it's important to balance business needs with engineering and architecture requirements. I enjoy working in innovative products that fit the users needs.

I strongly believe in continuous improvement. That's why I always seek opportunities to learn and embrace new challenges.

Gathered experience working on the full stack: aws cloud services, infrastructure, deployments, web and mobile application.

I am looking for a 100% remote job, I could negotiate if it is hybrid or in offices.

## **CORE QUALIFICATIONS:**

- Cloud (AWS, Google).
- Contact Centers (AWS Amazon Connect, Lex, Contact Lens).
- Development of TPV in real time, with a payment platform(OpenPay API).
- Geolocation (api google maps v3).
- Angular, React (hooks, Redux), Vue (SPA, real time WebSockets, GraphQL).
- Mobile apps (ionic-angular framework, Flutter, React Native (iOs, Android).
- Linux / Unix server management, Docker, AWS-EC2, AWS-EBS, ECS, EKS.
- Api's Rest (NodeJS(express) or Python(Fastapi, Flask, Django) in AWS EC2 instances).
- Serverless microservices (AWS Lambda(NODE, PYTHON), AWS Api
   Gateway(Authorizers JsonWebTokens), AWS-SQS, AWS-SNS).
- PHP (Codeigniter, Laravel).

- .NET (ASP C# / Visual Basic).
- Design (normalization) and administration of SQL and NoSQL databases (SqlServer, MySql, Postgresql, MongoDB, DynamoDB).
- AWS (Lambda, Api Gateway, S3, SQS, Cloudwatch, RDS, EventBridge).
- **Unit tests** and Integration testing(**cypress**).
- CI/CD Using pipelines, automated deployments with jenkins to AWS.
- Using docker and dev-containers for development in VS-Code.

## **SKILLS**

Critical Thinking, Problem Solving, Time Management, Effective Communication, Teamwork, Resolving technical issues, Faster learner, Learn mindset, Coaching, Mentoring, Active listening, Abstract thinking, Honesty, Adaptability.

#### FRONT END:

- I have advanced knowledge on HTML, CSS3 and JavaScript (from ES1 to ES2020).
- I have used typescript in both the frontend and backend.
- CSS (Advanced knowledge): Flexbox, CSS Grid, responsive design (Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap).
- React Js (Advanced knowledge): Creating Class and Functional components, hooks, redux, hoc, styled-components.
- Angular (Advanced knowledge): Creating components, modules, services
  from angular cli, using redux or services to share the state, rxjs, protect the
  routes using guards.
- Vue (Advanced knowledge): Creating components, sharing the state using vuex(actions, mutations, getters, store).
- Using AWS S3 to deploy and cloudflare DNS.

#### **BACK END:**

- Serverless microservices: (AWS Lambda(NODE, PYTHON), AWS Api
   Gateway(Authorizers), AWS-SQS).
- Python: Real time apps using socket.io, FastApi, Flask, Django, AWS
   Lambda(serverless).
- Node: Express (socket.io), AWS Lambda(Serverless).
- PHP: Laravel.
- Java: Spring, Spring Boot, Spring Data, Spring Security.
- Servers: Managing EC2 instances, VPS through SSH connection.

#### **DATABASES:**

#### SQL:

- MYSQL
- POSTGRESQL
- SQL SERVER
- AURORA (mysql postgresql)

#### NO SQL:

- Mongo db
- Dynamo DB

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### LumSton

Cloud Operations | July 2022 at present.

## Technologies:

- Frontend (Angular(typescrcipt), HTML, CSS, Tailwind).
- Backend (NodeJs, NestJs, Typescript, TypeOrm).
- Microservices serverless (AWS Lambda (NodeJs, Python), AWS ApiGateway, AWS RDS, AWS SNS, AWS DynamoDB, MongoDB, EventBridge, CloudWatch)
- Amazon Connect, Amazon Lex, Amazon Contact Lens (Create contact centers, programming the contact flow, recording calls to apply Al and analyze sentiments and improve the user experience)

## **Clip** (Es la plataforma líder de pagos digitales y comercio)

Sr. Fullstack developer | October 2021 - June 2022.

## Technologies:

- Front (JavaScript, Angular, React, HTML, CSS).
- Microservicios serverless (AWS Lambda (NodeJs, Python), AWS ApiGateway, AWS RDS, AWS DyanmosDB, MongoDB)
- AWS CloudFormation
- Git, GitHub, Jenkins
- Java, Spring Boot

#### **Numina Mx**

Full-stack developer | from December 2019 to November 2021.

- HTML, CSS(Responsive web design, Flexbox, CSS Grid)
- JavaScript (Angular, React(hooks), Vue)
- AWS (Lambda(Python3, NodeJs), Api Gateway, S3)
- Terraform, Packer
- Automated deployments to stage or production
- Unit Testing and code quality check(Sonarq)

I developed this website: <a href="https://www.numina.mx/">https://www.numina.mx/</a> using react, styled-components, only css, without using UI libraries.

#### Envíoclick

Full-stack developer | from April 2019 to December 2019.

- Migrate application made in (Laravel, vue is) to Microservices
- JavaScript (Angular, React(hooks), Vue from laravel monolithic app)
- AWS (Lambda(Python3, NodeJs), Api Gateway, S3)
- Correction of bugs and development of features for app in Angular
- Automated deployments to stage or production
- Unit Testing and code quality check(Sonarq)

I developed this website: <a href="https://www.envioclick.com/mx">https://www.envioclick.com/mx</a> using react, styled-components

# Copiloto Satelital de Grupo Michelin (Ciudad de México)

Full-stack developer | from Mayo 2018 to April 2019.

- Design and development of a multiplatform application (ionic-angular), currently for android available in the PlayStore (Back-end / Front-end, store publication)
- .Net webApi (apiRestFul), NodeJS.
- SqlServer (Stored procedure)
- Git, BitBucket
- Bug fixes and improvements to the vehicle monitoring platform with GPS
- WebServices, WCF (.net, asp, C#, VB, SQL Server)
- Microservices (NodeJS, MongoDB(mongoose), SQL Server)

# Mx-Race (Ciudad de México)

Developer | from December 2015 to April 2018.

- Design and development of an electronic timing system (.NET, SQL Server)
- Web Platform (html5, css3, js, bootstrap)), publication of results in real time (WebServices PHP)
- Design, development and implementation of an Enrollment System for athletic races charged to a credit / debit card
- Development of registration platforms for employees of private sports races (Grupo BAL, NISSAN Unbreakable, Deloitte, Grupo DESC - KUO, Dupont, Sagarpa, GEEP, BANXICO, Metlife).

https://www.mx-race.com/eventos/, https://time-mx.com/misinscripciones/, https://time-mx.com/resultados/unbreakable/2018/veracruz/

## **EDUCATION**

# Lic. Sistemas Computarizados e Informática

Universidad Loyola del Pacífico, ULP. (Grade point average: 9.1) (AUGUST 2006 - FEBRUARY 2011 - En proceso de titulación)

Address: Avenida Heroico Colegio Militar s/n, Acapulco Guerrero.

# **High School**

Colegio de Bachilleres #24 (AUGUST 2003 - June 2006)

Address: Plan de los Amates, Acapulco Guerrero.